Okay, I have a slight confession. I've
been showing you the old way to declare
functions. And we've actually over the
years evolved to have nicer ways of
declaring functions that take a lot of
less time to type and they're just a lot
smaller and they take up a lot less
space on the page. Um, and so I'm going
to kind of walk you through that
evolution so that you'll understand the
newer functions when you see them
written. So let's start by defining a
function. We'll call our function um
clean up string and we're going to write
the same function we took we wrote in
the last video. Well, this function
takes an input of a messy string.
It does some work. Um so we said messy
string equals messy string.trim.percase
and then we returned messy string. So
what this does is it takes an input
string, trims it, uppercases it, stores
it in a variable, and then returns it.
Well, we can actually write this a lot
shorter. So we can say function cleanup
string, and we'll take in a messy
string.
And then on the next line, we're going
to return
messy string.trim.percase.
So what we've done is we've condensed
doing work and returning into the same
line. So now we're doing our work and
then immediately outputting it, which is
cool and it's definitely shorter. Um,
but let's make this even shorter. So
let's look at this function and
determine what parts of it actually
matter. Well, creating a name, that
seems helpful. If we want to call it
later, we probably need to give it a
name. Um, we definitely need to take
input. It wouldn't be a function if it
doesn't take input. It wouldn't be a
function if it doesn't do work. And it
wouldn't be a function if it doesn't
return output. Um, or at least generally
functions take input, do work, and give
an output. So, let's see. When we write
a function that takes input, we use
parentheses.
When we do work, we use curly braces.
And when we give output, we use the word
return.
So that right there seems to be to me
the key points of this function. So then
why are we typing the word function over
and over? If we know generally that
something with parenthesis is a
function, then do we really need the
keyword function? Well, I'm going to
show you a shorter way of writing this.
So well, we want to create a name. And
we know that a variable, so I could say
let my var equal clean up string. We
know a variable can equal a function.
So if we know that this and then now we
could call that function by typing my
var and putting parenthesis and giving
it the messy string that it needs. So we
know we can write a function and then
store it in a variable and then we can
call that function by using that
variable's name.
We also know that the required parts of
a function are input, work and output.
And that can be typically written like
this.
So let's apply that to make this
function syntax shorter. So I'm going to
comment this out and I'm going to
comment this out. And so one way we
could do this is we could do const or
the word let to create a variable. And
we're going to call it clean
up string.
And then we're going to set it equal to
a function. Well, I told you the
important part of a function is
parenthesis. and then curly braces and
return. So let's create parenthesis
and then let's do curly braces and
return and a semicolon. So you'll notice
that there is a red squiggly and it
tells you what it's expecting. It's kind
of spoiling my surprise. Um but we know
that we need to take some input. So
let's put that here. So we'll say messy
string and we know that we need to
return some output. Well, what are we
returning? Well, we were able to
simplify it to just this line right
here. So we'll copy it and we'll paste
it. We're going to return messy
string.trim.2 uppercase. Well, as it
happens, if you want to declare a
function this way, you do need one
special character. And that special
character is um the arrow function. So
you put an equal sign and a greater than
sign. And that creates an arrow. What
that does is it says, "Hey, we're going
to take some input between the curly
braces. We're going to do some work. And
wherever you find the return is where
we're going to give some output. So this
line of code right here is the exact
same thing as lines 15 through 17. We
gave it a name, we took input,
and then we did some work and returned
output on a single line like you did in
line 16.
Um, and in the next video I'll show you
how to shorten it even